Raluca-Dana Ciure

☐ raluciure | in raluca-ciure | ⊕ raluca-website | ✓ ralu.ciure@gmail.com | ■ +40 741420187

Summary

Human-Computer Interaction master graduate. With Project Management experience, and a background in Computer Engineering, Innovation, and Entrepreneurship, my goal is to bring digital interactions to new heights, while focusing on the needs of the users and brand awareness.

Work Experience

Project Portfolio Manager - SES, Luxembourg

Feb 2024 - Aug 2024

- Utilized big data analytics skills and large volume database queries to support and enhance Project Portfolio reporting systems, developing data-driven insights with Power BI for more informed decisionmaking.
- Led an initiative to reduce company software license costs, successfully transitioning 70% of employees from premium to basic plans, resulting in significant cost savings;
- Conducted predictive analysis and modeling using Monte Carlo simulation at both organizational and project levels, providing accurate future forecasts and improving project planning accuracy.

Software Developer - Zenitech, Romania

Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

- Designed and implemented the back-end of a web application using Golang and the Google Maps API, enabling architects to upload their work and have corresponding areas dynamically drawn on the map.
- Developed both the front-end (React Native) and back-end (Java Spring) components of a web/mobile application for digital inventory management, streamlining the company's inventory processes.

EDUCATION

2022 - 2024 MSc in Human-Computer Interaction and Design at Aalto University and Technical University of Madrid

2018 - 2022 BSc in Computer Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

SKILLS

Analytical skills Agile/Scrum Methodologies, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Business

> Objects, Business Modeling, Market Analysis, Value Proposition Canvas, PEST and SWOT analysis, SEO/SEM Analysis, Business Insights, Data in-

terpretation, Market Data, Presentation, Strategic communication

Software development JavaScript, HTML/CSS, React, Angular, Flutter, Android Studio, Java,

Spring, Hibernate, Python, MySQL

UI/UX Design User research, Usability testing, Heuristics evaluation, Wireframing, low-fi and

high-fi prototyping, Accessibility principles (WCAG), Figma, A/B Testing.

Tools Git, Jira, Power BI, Microsoft Azure, Tableau, Blender

Languages Romanian - native — English - fluent — French and Spanish - intermediate

Publications

Ciure, Raluca-Dana et al. (2022). "Spike sorting using Superlets: Evaluation of a novel feature space for the discrimination of neuronal spikes". In: 2022 IEEE 18th International Conference on Intelligent Computer Communication and Processing (ICCP), pp. 229-235. DOI: 10.1109/ICCP56966.2022. 10053955.